(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
Otonose Kanade BIRTHDAY LIVE 2026 I PROGRESS
[Title: Otonose Kanade BIRTHDAY LIVE 2026 I PROGRESS]
幽閉利口逝く前に
Locking up the clever one before they die
ユーヘイじゃ利口に難儀ダーリン
You, hey, it's a pain to get you to be obedient, darling
幽閉ストップ知ってないし
Don't lock me up! It's not like I knew
勘弁にしといてなんて惨忍
Give me a break! You're so cruel
人様願う欠片のアイロニ
The wishes of the people feel like scraps of irony
だれもが願う無機質なような
Everyone's wishing for something mechanical
一足先に始めてたいような
Wanting to get in on it before everyone else
先が見えないヴァージンハッピーショー
A virgin happy show where nobody knows what's next
無いの新たにお願い一つ
I don't have a single brand-new wish
愛も変わらずおまけに
It's the same as ever, and on top of that
ワーニングワーニング
Warning, warning
無いのあなたにお願い一つ
I have one wish for you
張り詰めた思い込め
Putting all my built-up feelings into it
レフトサイドライトサイド
Left side, right side
歯をむき出してパッパッパッ照れくさいね
Baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa, this is so embarrassing
レフトサイドライトサイド
Left side, right side
歯を突き出してパッパッパッ
Let your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa
ハハ、you are king
Haha, you are king
you are king
無邪気に遊ぶ
Playing innocently
期待期待のダーリンダーリン
You're the darling, darling that I've been wishing for
健気に笑う痛い痛いの消える
Laughing admirably, all of my pain disappears
無様にしねる苦い思いもなくなって
Dying clumsily, my bitter feelings fading away
ラララブウラッタッタ
Lo-lo-love, ra-ta-ta
嫌い嫌いの最低泣いてダウン
I hate it, I hate it, it's the worst - crying and down
毎度新たにお願い一つ
Just as always, here's a brand-new wish
愛も変わらずピックアップの
The same as ever, with no picked-out
ワーニングワーニング
Warning, warning
無いのあなたにお願い一つ
I have one wish for you
張り詰めた思い込め
Putting all my built-up feelings into it
レフトサイドライトサイド
Left side, right side
歯をむき出してパッパッパッ邪魔くさいね
Baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa, this is so bothersome
レフトサイドライトサイド
Left side, right side
歯を突き出してパッパッパッ
Let your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa
ハハ、you are king
Haha, you are king
you are king
どんな夢を見に行こうか
What kind of dream shall we go see?
正しさばかりに恐れ戦かないで
Don't tremble in fear of only what is "right"
自由自在に飛び回って
Fly around freely
ステップ・バイ・ステップ ビートを刻んで
Step by step, mark the beat
果ての無いパーティーを 続けようか
Shall we continue this endless party?
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump into this era
今夜この街を飛び立って
Fly out of this city tonight
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the great sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この風に飛び乗って
Jump into this wind
今夜台風の目となって
Become the eye of the typhoon tonight
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the great sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
代わり映えがしない日常の
In our mundane daily lives
片隅で無邪気に 笑っていられたらいいよな
It would be nice if we could laugh innocently in a corner of it
無意味な旅を続けようか
Shall we continue this meaningless journey?
ワン・バイ・ワン 一歩ずつでいいさ
One by one, step by step is fine
歓声も罵声も 呑み込んで
Swallow both cheers and boos
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump into this era
今夜愚かな杭となって
Become a foolish stake tonight
過ちを恐れないで
Don't be afraid of mistakes
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この風に飛び乗って
Jump into this wind
今夜名も無き風となって
Become a nameless wind tonight
清濁を併せ呑んで
Swallow both clear and muddy things
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
大雨降らせ
Let it rain heavily
大地震わせ
Let the earth shake
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Shoulder the tomorrow
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
大雨降らせ
Let it rain heavily
大地震わせ
Let the earth shake
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Shoulder the tomorrow
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
大雨降らせ
Let it rain heavily
大地震わせ
Let the earth shake
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Shoulder the tomorrow
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
大雨降らせ
Let it rain heavily
大地震わせ
Let the earth shake
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Shoulder the tomorrow
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump into this era
今夜この街を飛び立って
Fly out of this city tonight
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the great sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この風に飛び乗って
Jump into this wind
今夜台風 of the 目となって
Become the eye of the typhoon tonight
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the great sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
貴女の期待に飛び乗って
Jump into your expectations
今夜この羽根で飛びたくて
I want to fly with these wings tonight
この大空を飛びたくて
I want to fly in this great sky
命生まれ 命生まれ
Life is born, life is born
この風に飛び乗って
Jump into this wind
今夜名も無き風となって
Become a nameless wind tonight
清濁を併せ呑んで
Swallow both clear and muddy things
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
イェーイ！
Yeah!
ヴィーナス
作詞：ナナホシ管弦楽団　作曲：岩見陸
[Venus]
Lyrics: Nanahoshi Orchestra / Composition: Riku Iwami
泡になって　海を越え
Becoming foam, crossing the sea,
季節をまた　連れてくる
bringing the season once again.
貝殻に
To the seashell,
耳澄ます
I listen closely.
静寂にも
Even in the silence,
声は探す
I search for a voice.
教えておくれ
Please tell me,
この風はどこから吹いているの
where is this wind blowing from?
そこにいるの
Are you there?
時間よどうか待って
Time, please wait.
僕だけが祈っている
I am the only one praying.
生まれる前に
Before being born,
出会っていたよ
we had already met.
寄せては返す
Washing over and retreating,
足跡も消して
erasing even our footprints.
近づくほどに
The closer I get,
遠ざかる　あなた
the further away you go, my...
ヴィーナス
...Venus.
風に認めた歌
A song penned in the wind.
さざめく波になりたい
I want to become rustling waves.
もの言わぬ貝でありたい
I want to be a silent shell.
待っている
I'm waiting,
想っている
I'm thinking of you.
絶やさぬ人になりたい
I want to be someone who never lets things die.
底知れぬ愛を知りたい
I want to know boundless love.
待っている
I'm waiting,
縋っている
I'm clinging.
雨なく花は咲かない
Flowers don't bloom without rain.
名残に触れ　別れない
Touching the lingering traces, we cannot separate,
去っていく
leaving,
leaving.
あなたが誰か知らない
I don't know who you are,
なのに探さずにはいられない
and yet I can't help but search for you.
去っていく
Leaving,
拾っていく
gathering
欠片
fragments...
欠片ーー！
...fragments!
夢に明け暮れて
Spending day and night in dreams,
定義も秤にかけたまま
leaving even definitions weighed on the scale,
置いていくの
leaving them behind.
薄れるよう願って
Wishing for it to fade,
幸せを祈っている
I pray for your happiness.
眠れるように
So that I can sleep,
握っては目覚め
holding hands then waking up.
大人になれば
If I become an adult,
溜め息も消えて
even my sighs will disappear.
生きてくほどに
The more I live,
遠のいていくの
the further away it goes,
ヴィーナス
Venus.
いつか思い出す
Someday I will remember.
生まれる前に
Before being born,
出会っていたよ
we had already met.
寄せては返す
Washing over and retreating,
足跡も消して
erasing even our footprints.
近づくほどに
The closer I get,
遠ざかる　あなた
the further away you go, my...
ヴィーナス
...Venus.
風に認めた歌
A song penned in the wind.
背が伸びたから
Because I've grown taller...
ねえ　きっと愛でしょう
...hey, it must be love.
砂に埋もれた保存
Buried in the sand,
涙も返して
return even my tears.
生まれ変われど
Even if I am reborn,
もう一度あなたの
once again, your...
ヴィーナス
...Venus,
微笑み抱いていたい
I want to hold onto your smile.
ヴィーナス
Venus,
巡り逢えた暖かな音
the warm sound of our meeting!
はい！
Yes!
ということで、始まりました！
And with that, we have begun!
音乃瀬奏生誕祭2026！
Otonose Kanade Birthday Festival 2026!
見に来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to watch!
ふぅ、ふぅ！
Phew, phew!
ちょっと駆け足でね、2曲お届けしましたが、いかがでしたでしょうか？
I performed two songs in a bit of a rush, but how did you like them?
たくさんコメント、パチパチありがとう！
Thank you so much for all the comments and claps!
見えてるよー！ありがとう！
I can see them! Thank you!
はい、そしてね、ハッシュタグ、えー、こちら
Yes, and the hashtag... here...
えー、画面にも出ているんですが
It's displayed on the screen,
#音乃瀬奏生誕祭2026 でいっぱいポストしてください！
please post a lot with #OtonoseKanadeBirthdayFestival2026!
ちょっとこの配信が終わったらエゴサーチをするなり、いっぱいね、見に行くので
Once this stream ends, I'll do some egosearching and look at them,
感想とか、ここが良かったよ、とか呟いてくれたら、とっても嬉しいです！
so I'd be super happy if you tweeted your thoughts or what parts you liked!
ハッピーバースデーありがとう！
Thank you for the happy birthdays!
ふぅ、ふぅ！
Phew, phew!
えー、こちらの配信ですね、あの、タイトル、ライブのタイトル
Also, the title of this stream, the live title...
「In Progress」というタイトルになっています。
...is "In Progress".
ちょっとね、どういう意味かなーって
I'm sure you were wondering what it means,
お前ら、いっぱい推測してくれたと思うんですが、大体合ってました。すごい！
and you guessed a bunch of things, but you were mostly right. Amazing!
こちらのタイトルですね、こちらの英語には「未完成」という
For this title, in English, it has the meaning of "incomplete" or...
意味が含まれていまして、
...has that meaning included in it.
ま、奏のなんだろうな、今の未完成ながら進むというスタンスをこのライブでお見せできればなと思います。
Well, I hope I can show you Kanade's stance of moving forward despite being incomplete in this live performance.
はい、ちょっとまだ自分にこうなんだろう、完全に満足しきっていないけど、まだまだ止まらず今に安堵せず進んでいくぞっていう、そういう意味を込めての「In Progress」というタイトルにさせていただきました！
Yes, I'm still not completely satisfied with myself, but I chose the title "In Progress" to mean that I will keep moving forward without stopping or resting on my laurels!
はい！ま、ちょっとね、えー、駆け足で、えー、紹介していったということで、奏、ちょっとお水飲んでいきたいんですけど、ダンサーさんたち！
Yes! Well, since I introduced things in a bit of a rush, Kanade wants to go drink some water, but dancers!
場を繋いでもらえたりしますかねー？
Could you keep things going while I'm away?
無理？
No way?!
無理じゃない！やるんだよ！
It's not impossible! You've got to do it!
はい、お願いします。なんか面白い動きとか。いっぱいお願いします！
Yes, please. Like, some funny moves. Lots of them, please!
ないしょ。
It's a secret.
ないしょ！？
Secret?!
え、ちょっと、パワハラ奏みたい感じになりましたがですね、あの普段ね、奏のダンスの指導をしてくださっているとっても優しい先生たちですよ、そうですよね？
Well, that felt a bit like Power Harassment Kanade, but these are actually the very kind teachers who usually instruct Kanade's dancing, right?
はい。
Yes.
言わせたみたいな。ちょっと今日の意気込み、なんか「うおー！」とかで言ってもらえたりしますか？
Like I forced you to say it. Could you give us your enthusiasm for today, like "Wooo!" or something?
頑張ります！
We'll do our best!
イェーイ！ダンサーさんたちもたくさんありがとうございました！
Yay! Thank you so much to the dancers as well!
では、では、では。次はゲストパートになります。
So, so, so. Next up is the guest part.
最初は誰かな？
Who will be the first?
ちょっと楽しみということで、じゃ、早速次の曲いきましょう。
I'm really looking forward to it, so let's get straight into the next song.
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Still, I wanted to dance
眠れないくらい
To the point I couldn't sleep
情熱の火はいつしか いつの日にか
Before I knew it, the fire of passion, someday...
はなから気付いている 焔はいつか消える
I've known it from the start, that the flame will someday die out
ねぇ なにも要らないはずだった
Hey, I wasn't supposed to need anything
なのにまだ I'm so serious
And yet, I'm still so serious
ああまだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time
ああただ burn it up
Ah, just burn it up
Baby Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ Bourgeoisie
Baby, sorry darling, it's not that sweet
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But surely it's not that bad
Give me fire Light it up Baby 燃やしちゃうぜ
Give me fire, light it up baby, I'll burn it all down
yeah
Yeah 千代も八千代 変わりもせずに
Yeah, through a thousand, eight thousand generations, without changing
全部燃やせ八百屋お七
Burn it all down, Yaoya Oshichi
出でよ舞えよ火の粉 焚き付けるのが仕事
Come forth, dance, sparks, fanning the flames is my job
燃えるさまはお見事 火遊びはしない ぬるいまね出来ない
The way it burns is magnificent, no playing with fire, no half-hearted tricks
燃やし尽くすマグマドラマ この飽くなき渇き
A magma drama burning everything down, this insatiable thirst
青い炎みたい 死は過去のひとつ隣
Like a blue flame, death is just next door to the past
Turn it up, turn it up, turn it up!
Sorry darling, hurry up... ああ、まだ間に合う...
Sorry darling, hurry up... Ah, we can still make it...
Give me fire, light it up baby, 燃やしちゃうぜ
Give me fire, light it up baby, I'll burn it all up!
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
But I still wanted to dance...
Wow!
Happy Birthday! / Thank you very much!
Thank you very much! / Birthday girl! / Yeah! Birthday girl!
まず最初のゲストは、Mori Calliope先輩に来ていただきました！
First of all, our first guest is Mori Calliope-senpai!
初めまして！Hi everybody! Yo yo, what's up? It's Mori Calliope here today to celebrate Kanade's special birthday.
Nice to meet you! Hi everybody! Yo yo, what's up? It's Mori Calliope here today to celebrate Kanade's special birthday.
わー！Kanadeの誕生日をお祝いしに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Wow! Thank you so much for coming to celebrate my birthday!
Oh yeah! I was so nervous! / 緊張してた！
Oh yeah! I was so nervous! / I was nervous!
ラップする前、「ヤバい、ヤバい、できない、できない、できない」と思ってた...
Before the rap, I was thinking, "Oh no, oh no, I can't do this, I can't do this..."
いやいやいや、全然感じなかったですよ、そんな！
No, no, no, I didn't feel that at all!
難しい、日本語のラップ...
Japanese rap is so difficult...
めちゃくちゃカッコよかったです！
But you were incredibly cool!
Kanade-chanもカッコよかったよ！
Kanade-chan, you were cool too!
嬉しい！一緒に、いい感じになりました！
I'm so happy! We made a great duo!
一緒に歌いたかったんですよ！
I really wanted to sing together with you!
私も！ / Calliope先輩のラップが大好きで...
Me too! / I love your rap, Calliope-senpai...
あの、「Beyond the Way」でも実は歌わせていただいた、ご一緒させていただいたりしましたから、それ以来じゃないですか？
Actually, we got to sing together in "Beyond the Way", so is this the first time since then?
そうですね。あんまり機会がなくて。でも今回すごかった！
That's right. We didn't have many opportunities. But this time was amazing!
わ、嬉しい！ / ぶちかましました！
Wow, I'm happy! / We crushed it!
ぶちかましました！それ奏もやりたいけど、今スカートだからできないよ。
We crushed it! I want to do that pose too, but I'm wearing a skirt right now so I can't.
スタミナ、スタミナ！ / スタミナ、先輩に分けてもらおう、スタミナ！
Stamina, stamina! / I should ask you to share some of your stamina, senpai!
お水たくさん飲んで！ / はい！ありがとうございます！
Drink lots of water! / Yes! Thank you!
お水飲みにいってこようかな。 / Go, go, yes, yes, yes!
Maybe I'll go get some water. / Go, go, yes, yes, yes!
Hi everybody! Kanade-chan's water time. What's up? I'm Mori Calliope.
Abura... I did it!
Abura!
ちょっと忘れちゃうと思ってたけど、できた！
I thought I'd forget, but I did it!
生歌すごい好きだから、今回誘ってくれてありがとうございます！
I really love live singing, so thank you so much for inviting me!
こちらこそ、ありがとうございます！本当に一緒に歌えてすごく光栄でした！
Thank you so much as well! It was truly an honor to sing with you!
またやろう！
Let's do it again!
またぜひご一緒させてください！
Please let me join you again!
ということで、Calliope先輩ありがとうございました！
So, thank you so much, Calliope-senpai!
ありがとうございました！これからも頑張ってね、good luck! / ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! Keep doing your best, good luck! / Thank you!
You can do it! Peace! Bye bye! / Thank you very much! Bye bye!
バイバイ！
Bye bye!
ということで、Calliope先輩との『火炎』でした！
So, that was our performance of 'Kaen' with Calliope-senpai!
次の曲行く前にちょっと熱いから、ちょっと着替えてきてもいいですか？
Before going to the next song, it's a bit hot, so can I go change my clothes?
待っててくださいね！
Please wait for me!
ふぅ！ちょっとジャケット脱いできました！ちょっと熱気がすごい！
Phew! I took off my jacket! The heat here is amazing!
お前らもいっぱい、かけ...ありがとう、ありがとうございます！コメント見えてるよ！
Everyone, thank you for all your cheers! I can see your comments!
では、早速次の曲いきましょうかね。
Now, let's head straight to the next song.
ゲストは誰か、楽しみですね。
I wonder who the next guest is. It's exciting!
では、聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
語れない 眠れない トロイメライ
Unspeakable, sleepless, dreams.
あなたの見てる正体
The true identity you see.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart that no one can read.
不可思議 知りたいだけ
Just wanting to know the mystery.
嘘も 現実も
Both lies and reality.
どっちも 真実だったの
They were both the truth.
...カルテ
...chart...
自意識 溢れ出して
...and an overflowing self-consciousness.
鼓動 世界像
Beating, world image...
いつも噛み合わないの
It's always a bit off,
痛くて
it hurts.
毎夜 ねがいごと
Every night I wish,
なんにも疑わないで
I don't want to doubt anything,
混ざり融け合いたい
and I want to melt together.
たわいない 判らない 理由 存在
Silly, I don't know, reasoning, existing...
あなたと残す後悔
Regrets left with you.
誰も読めないカルテ
A chart that no one can read,
不愉快 繰り返して
repeating the unpleasantness.
正しい夢は
Is a correct dream,
かなしい声は
a sad voice,
美しい? 疑わしい? 羨ましい?
beautiful? Doubtful? Enviable?
ねえ、どれ?
Hey, which one?
語れない眠れないトロイメライ
I can't talk, I can't sleep, Traumerei,
あなたの見てる正体
the true identity you are seeing.
誰も読めないカルテ
A chart that no one can read.
不可思議 知りたいだけ
I just want to know the wonder.
終わらないことはない トロイメライ
There is nothing that doesn't end, Traumerei,
あなたと跨ぐ境界
the boundary I cross with you.
誰も読めないカルテ
A chart that no one can read.
思春期 疵口 胸のうち
Adolescence, wounds, inside my chest...
不可思議 知りたいだけ
I just want to know the wonder.
はい！ということで！
Yes! And with that!
にじさんじから町田ちまさんに来ていただきましたー！
From Nijisanji, we have Machita Chima-san here with us!
おまえらの皆さん、こんばんは！上から読んでも下から読んでも町田ちまです！
Good evening to all of Omaera! Whether you read it forward or backward, I'm Machita Chima!
わーい！ちまさんにも「おまえら」が浸透してる！
Yay! "Omaera" has reached Chima-san as well!
もちろん知っています！
Of course I know!
知ってるんですか？
You knew?!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
めでたいめでたい
Congratulations, congratulations!
何ですか、その動きは？
What is that movement?
あ、これやっちゃうんです、これ
Ah, I just end up doing this.
あ、やっちゃう...癖なんですか？
Ah, you do... Is it a habit?
癖なんです
It's a habit.
それ、ちょっとリハーサルの時もやってて...
You were doing that during the rehearsal too...
やめて、ばらすのやめてください！
Stop, please don't expose me!
変な動きが出るんですね
So you make weird movements, I see.
うん、でも今日はちょっと大人しくね、お話します
Yeah, but today I'll talk a bit more calmly.
なるほど、ちょっと出てましたけど、全然出してもらっても大丈夫ですからね
I see. It slipped out a bit, but it's totally fine to show it!
あの、そういえば、ちまさんとはですね、先日、一緒に「空想列車」という楽曲の「歌ってみた」をコラボさせていただきまして...
Um, by the way, with Chima-san, we recently collaborated on a cover of the song "Kuusou Ressha"...
せていただきました！
We did!
本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
こちらこそ、お誘いいただいて本当に嬉しかった！
Likewise, I was so happy you invited me!
そうですか？やったー！
Really? Yay!
もう、ちまさんの透明な歌声に絶対に似合うだろうなと思って...
I thought it would absolutely suit Chima-san's clear singing voice...
「空想列車」もそうだし、今回の「不可思議のカルテ」も絶対に似合うだろうなと思って選曲させていただきました
so I chose both "Kuusou Ressha" and this time's "Fukashigi no Karte."
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しいです！
I'm so happy we could sing together!
私も幸せです！
I'm happy too!
でも、からで、なんか一個気になってることがあって...
But, there's one thing I've been wondering about...
何でしょう？
What is it?
空想列車のコメント欄に、なんか、「化け物」って書いてあったんですけど、ちまさんのこと。
In the comment section of "Kuusou Ressha," someone wrote "monster" about Chima-san.
うん
Yes.
それは何なんですか？
What's up with that?
多分、別人？あの、違う人のことを言ってるのかなって思うので、忘れてください。
Maybe it's another person? I think they're talking about someone else, so please forget it.
わかりました！そんな、こんな、こんな綺麗な、お姉さん...
Understood! There's no way such a beautiful lady...
そうよ、こんな、もうね...
Right, someone like this...
化け物なわけないですよね、今のコメントでも「化け物」って書いてあったけど、ちょっと見間違えてますよね、これ。
There's no way she's a monster. Though "monster" was written in the comments just now, they must be mistaken.
見間違えたよね、我々二人とも清楚だもんね。
They must have made a mistake. We are both pure and wholesome, after all.
もちろん！からでも清楚ですよ、そりゃあもう！
Of course! Kanade is pure too, absolutely!
はい！
Yes!
ということで、ちまさん、一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかったかったです！
So, Chima-san, I was so happy to sing with you!
こちらこそ！嬉しかった！
Me too! I was so happy!
嬉しかったです。よかったらまた、機会があったらまた、一緒に歌わせてください！
I was so happy. If you'd like, and if there's another opportunity, please let us sing together again!
いつでも歌いましょう！
Let's sing anytime!
やったー！言質取りました！
Yay! I got you on record!
やったやった！嬉しい。
Yay, yay! I'm happy.
じゃあ、この後も引き続き頑張ってください！
Well then, please keep doing your best for the rest of the show!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
応援してます！
I'm cheering for you!
ありがとうございます！まったねー！
Thank you! See you later!
またねー！
See you!
ということで、ちょっと奏もお水を飲んできてもいいですか？
So, can Kanade go drink some water too?
ちょっとだけお水飲んできます。
I'll go drink just a little bit of water.
まだまだまだまだ続いていきますよ！
We're still keeping this going!
次は誰かしら？あと二人ですね。
Who's next? There are two people left.
1/2の確率。それでは楽しみにしてください。
A 1 in 2 chance. Well, please look forward to it.
次の曲、行くぞ！
The next song... Here we go!
G4L
あれが正解なんて
Are those the right answers?
誰の成れの果て？（なんだっての悶々々）
Whose end results are those? (What's with this, sigh sigh sigh)
答えも欲しいのも一個てこれだけ
Answers and things I want, one of them, just this much
悩んだってしょうがないじゃんね
It's no use worrying about it, you know
あれは夢だったって思うことにしたって（つら）
Even if I decided to think that was just a dream (pain)
でも全然思えないんだけど
But I can't think that at all
助けてよ　フォロワー！
Help me, follower!
抗うだけ
Just fighting back
若さに負け
Losing to youth
next, next
lucky lucky lucky!
（アーリーオ）
(Early-o)
割り切れたらさ
If I could just accept it
（オーリーオ）
(Oori-o)
楽なのに　とか
It'd be easier, or so...
あぁ…もうヤダ
Ahh... I've had enough
なんという新世界か
What kind of new world is this?
あなた以外は
Other than you
あなた以外はいらない　ない　ない
I don't need anyone else, none, none
はらないでよ　バリア
Don't put up a barrier
あるはずなの何か
There should be something
あったならば　happy! jumpin’ yeah!
If there is, happy! jumpin' yeah!
あなたのその手と
Your hand
あたしのこの手を
and my hand
つないだらもう二度と離さないわ
If we hold them, we'll never let go again
あなたのその手があたしのこの手を
Your hand and my hand
掴んだら
If you grab it
以後お見知りおきを my love♡
Nice to meet you from now on, my love♡
これで終わりなんて
Is this the end?
アガれないままなんて（鳴いちゃってポンポンポン）
Without being able to rise (crying, pon pon pon)
どうにかなっちゃえって願って願ってね
Wishing and wishing that something would happen, right?
朝帰りしたり　しちゃわん？どう？
Hey, maybe we could stay out all night, what do you think?
なあもう我慢できん
Nah, I can't take it anymore
pain, pain
痛いってば everyday
It hurts every day
ま、ゆーていけるけどなブルベ夏なんで関係ないな
Well, I can say that, I'm a cool summer type anyway, it doesn't matter
誰よりもネコ
More catty than anyone else
節操ないも結構
Lack of discipline is also fine
あーしはあーしだ見といてよ ready
I am who I am, just watch me, ready
もう今日で終わらせたいなって
I want to end it today
リスタートできたらって
If I could restart
でも無理よ
But it's impossible
もう…
Already...
what’s on your mind?
what's on your mind?
（アーリーオ）
(Early-o)
割り切れたらさ
If I could accept it
（オーリーオ）
(Oori-o)
楽なのに　とか
It would be easier, or so
あぁ…もうヤダ
Ahh... I've had enough
なんという新世界か
What kind of new world is this?
あなた以外は
Other than you
あなた以外はいらない　ない　ない
I don't need anyone else, none, none
はらないでよ　バリア
Don't put up a barrier
あるはずなの何か
There should be something
あったならば　happy! jumpin’ yeah!
If there is, happy! jumpin' yeah!
あなたのその手と
Your hand
あたしのこの手を
and my hand
つないだらもう二度と離さないわ
If we hold them, we'll never let go again
あなたのその手があたしのこの手を
Your hand and my hand
掴んだら
If you grab it
以後お見知りおきを my love♡
Nice to meet you from now on, my love♡
お見知りおきを my love♡
はい！なんと3人目のゲストは、
Yes! Unbelievably, our third guest is...
同じく、にじさんじから戌亥とこさんに来ていただきました！
also from Nijisanji, Inui Toko-san! We have her here!
まいど！にじさんじ所属公式つよつよケルベロス、戌亥とこです！
Hello there! I'm Nijisanji's official super strong Cerberus, Inui Toko!
いぬいとこさん！
Inui Toko-san!
違う違う、戌亥とこです。
No, no, it's Inui Toko.
いぬいとこ？
Inui Toko?
戌亥とこ。
Inui Toko.
いぬいとこ？
Inui Toko?
戌亥とこ。
Inui Toko.
い！
I!
え、難しい！
Uh, that's hard!
いいよ、好きに呼んでいいですよ。
It's fine, you can call me whatever you like.
いぬいとこさん！
Inui Toko-san!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
Happy Birthday!
イェーイ！
Yay!
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too! はじめまして、はじめましてじゃない…
Nice to meet you too! Nice to meet you... wait, it's not "nice to meet you"...
はじめましてですよ。
It is "nice to meet you"!
今日、初めて会いました。
We met for the first time today.
今日、ガチのはじめまして。
Today is a literal first-time meeting!
いるの？今日ガチのはじめまして。
Are there actually first-time meetings today?
いない、いない、いない。
No, no, no...
はじめまして。
Nice to meet you.
はじめまして、ちょっと、
Nice to meet you, well...
ね、ちまさんと、カプセル・リレーションの歌ってみたでご一緒させていただいたんですけど、
Well, we did the "Capsule Relation" cover song together with Chima-san, but...
本当の本当の今日、はじめまして。
but today is the real, real first-time meeting.
本当のはじめまして。
The real first-time meeting.
はい。
Yes.
もう今日、はじめましての時、
And today, when we met for the first time,
あの、とこさんが楽屋に来ていただいて、
um, Toko-san came to the dressing room,
で、挨拶に来ていただいて。ありがとうございます。
and came to greet me. Thank you very much.
いえいえ、こちらこそ。
No, no, thank you.
で、なんかその時にお弁当が奏の部屋にあったから、
And at that time, there was some bento in Kanade's room, so
あ、よかったらお弁当食べますか？って言って、
I said, "Ah, would you like some bento if you want?"
あの、選んでください。カレーだったんですけど、カレーと、なんか付随するものがあるお弁当だったんですけど、
and, "please choose." It was curry, curry and some side dishes in the bento...
なんかトコさんが一言放ったんですよ
But Toko-san uttered a single word...
「芋だ！」って
...'Sweet potatoes!'
お芋が大好きなんです、私
I really love sweet potatoes.
芋？
Sweet potatoes?
そう、お芋めっちゃ好きなんですよ
Yes, I love sweet potatoes so much.
カレーなのに、芋？
Even though it was curry, sweet potatoes?
いや、お芋が好きやから
Well, because I love sweet potatoes.
芋好きなんだって思って、芋があるお弁当だったから
I realized she liked them, and since the bento had them...
「あ、良かった」って思って
...I thought, "Oh, thank goodness!"
じゃあちょっと芋一番大きいの選びますね、って言って
I said, "Then let me choose the biggest one for you."
そう、奏チョイスでね
Right, Kanade's choice.
選んで、別にそれをこう、あげようとしたわけじゃないんですけど
I chose it, not that I was trying to give it to her...
トコさんが、採用してくださって
...but Toko-san accepted my recommendation.
いや、それはするでしょ
Of course I would.
そんな、だってせっかくこれ一番お芋大きいですって選んでくれたら
I mean, since you picked the biggest sweet potato for me...
「あ、じゃあこれで」って
...I'd say, "Ah, then I'll take this one!"
"Ah, then I'll take this one!"
「じゃあこれにする」って
"Then I'll go with that one!"
めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです
I was so incredibly happy.
あの、なんか色んな味あったんですけど
There were actually various flavors,
もう芋の大きさだけで選んでましたよね
but you chose purely based on the size of the potato.
違う、違う！
No, no!
奏が選んでくれたから、持ってったんよ、私は
I took it because Kanade picked it out for me.
感動しました
I was so touched.
えっ、そうなんですか？
Wait, really?
そうよ
Yes.
大好き！
I love you!
よかったら、今後とも何か機会があったら
If you'd like, if there's ever another opportunity...
もちろん
Of course.
なんか一緒にやりましょう
...let's do something together.
いくらでもやろう、一緒に
Let's do it as much as you want.
本当ですか？ユニットも組みますか？
Really? Shall we form a unit too?
もうなんでもやろう、全部やろう。やりたいこと全部やろう
Let's do anything, everything! Let's do whatever we want.
本当ですか？じゃあユニット名...
Really? Then, the unit name...
「カルニス」で
...let's call it "Carnis"!
ちょっとかぶるか
That overlaps a bit, huh?
っていうのは冗談で、なんか
Just kidding, but...
一緒にできたら嬉しいです
...I'd be so happy if we could do something together.
一緒にやりましょう、ぜひ今後とも
Let's definitely work together in the future too.
ありがとうございました、ということでトコさん、ありがとう
Thank you very much. So, Toko-san, thank you...
ございました、この後も楽しみにしています
...very much. I'm looking forward to the rest of the show.
ありがとうございました、一緒に歌えてよかったです
Thank you so much! I'm glad we got to sing together.
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
ふう
*sighs*
ということでですね、次がゲストは最後になります決まってます
So then, the next guest will be our last.
最後はあの人って
The last guest is that person...
みんな分かるよね？
...so I'm sure you all know who it is, right?
楽しみにしててくださーい
Please look forward to it!
それでは次の曲いきます
Now, let's move on to the next song.
浪漫と算盤
[Song: The sun & moon (Roman to Soroban)]
主義（イズム）持て
Hold onto your principles, hold onto them...
持って利潤をうなしたならば割愛ばい
...if they bring in a profit, let's count it out.
着ない
Never wearing...
学衣ブチ壊し
...cap and gown, instead...
生の真理を宿す
...embedding our lives with truth.
義務解け
Fulfill your duties, fulfill them...
解いて理性を重んじつつも足掻くまで
...while respecting reason, struggle on.
待って
Wait...
漁算割り合えば
...if our calculations agree,
有耶無耶にしていたい
let's keep it ambiguous.
玄人衆
Experts,
素人衆
novices,
玄人衆
experts,
皆々労衆
everyone, the working class.
賛否両論頂戴
Give us both your praise and censure.
お気に召さずとも野暮
Even if you don't like it, it would be unrefined.
新しき技
Always showing off...
毎度繰り出してお相手
...new techniques to our partners.
苦しくとも僕らは解っている
Even if it's painful, we understand.
あなたも同じように
That you, just like us...
独り生きている
...are living all alone.
宇宙を
Showing off...
お見舞いする
...the universe...
向かい合った孤独同士が
...two solitudes facing each other.
自由と
Only freedom...
孤独だけが
...and loneliness...
待っているんでしょう
...are waiting, aren't they?
玄人手
Expert hands,
素人手
novice hands,
玄人手
expert hands,
労働者で生活者の算盤
calculations of the working class, of the living class.
おもしろ可笑しくさせて
Make it funny and amusing.
新しき理
Always painting...
毎度描き出してお相手
...a new truth to our partners.
虚しくともあなたは同じ旅人
Even if it's empty, you are a fellow traveler.
僕は許されていく
I am being forgiven,
夢とうつつを
distorting dream and reality...
歪めて
...to the end.
きっと、そう浪漫抱えたら
Surely, if we embrace romance...
算盤弾いて
and consult the abacus...
両極のど真ん中
aim for the very center of both extremes.
狙い撃て
Shoot to hit.
お願い 勇気をくれ
Please, give me courage...
疑わしい相手なら
Whenever dealing with a questionable partner,
いつだって
at any time,
自分 ずっと進化したいよね
I want to keep evolving myself, right?
答え合わせ
Let's compare our answers.
貴方を知るほど
The more I get to know you,
僕はただされていく
the more I feel corrected.
捨てたものじゃない_
It's not all bad.
ただ 生きようと
Simply striving to live.
うわー！
Whoa!
マイクが遠いぜ。
My mic is too far away.
体震えた！
My body was shaking!
何そのタフな持ち方...
What's with that tough grip...
え、ロッカーでしょ？ / イェーイ！
Eh, you're a rocker, right? / Yeah!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
いや、いいですね。スタンドマイクかっこいいじゃないですか！
Man, this is great. Stand mics look so cool!
かっこいいですよね！
They really are cool!
ね！おめでとうございます、本当に！
Right! Congratulations, seriously!
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much!
これちょっとウケるんだけど、もう一回いこう。せーの...
This is kind of funny, let's do it again. Ready, set...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
はい、ということで、最後のゲストはすいちゃん先輩でした！
Yes! So our final guest was Sui-chan senpai!
はい！ありがとうございます、呼んでくださって。
Yes! Thank you so much for having me.
彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石！アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
The star's rough gem that appeared like a comet! Idol VTuber Hoshimachi Suisei!
皆さんこんにちは！ / こんにちは！
Hello, everyone! / Hello!
おとのぜの皆さんなんですよね？
You are all the Otonoze, right?
あ、はい、そうです。正しい正式名称...
Ah, yes, that's right. The correct official name...
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
ね、おとのぜの皆さんいつもお前らと言われていますけども...
Right, the Otonoze folks are always called "you guys" though...
はい。いや、もう今回の『浪漫と算盤』という楽曲...
Yes. Well, for this song "Roman to Soroban"...
すいちゃん先輩と一緒に歌ったら絶対にカッコいいだろうと思って...
I thought it would be absolutely cool if I sang it with Sui-chan senpai...
まあ、カッコいいけどさ...
Well, it is cool, but...
生でやるもんじゃないよね！
It's not something you should do live, is it!
あははは！
Ahahaha!
もう私本当にさ、昨日とかさ、「歌える？歌える？歌えるかしら？」って、すごく不安だったけど...
Honestly, yesterday I was so anxious like, "Can I sing it? Can I really do it?" but...
今日合わせてみてね、よかったじゃん！
After practicing together today, it turned out great!
よかったです！
I'm so glad!
よかったんじゃない？
Didn't it turn out great?
メチャクチャ美声でしたよ！
Your voice was absolutely beautiful!
メチャクチャ美声でしたよ、お互い！
Both of our voices were absolutely beautiful!
え、ありがとうございます！嬉しい！
Eh, thank you! I'm so happy!
ね、コメント欄もね、うん。
Right, and looking at the comment section too...
「めっちゃよかった」「めっちゃよかった」「相性よかった」ほら、相性よかったって。
"It was so good," "so good," "great chemistry." See, they're saying our chemistry was great.
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
こうなったらまた歌ってくださいね、一緒に！
Since it went so well, please sing with me again!
え、あ、そうそう、なんか2人だけで歌うのは初めてなんだよね。
Oh, right, this is actually our first time singing as a duo, isn't it?
そうんです。『パンダヒーロー』で4人で一緒に歌うっていうことはあったんですけど、今回2人きりは初めてということで...
That's right. We sang together with four people in "Panda Hero," but this is the first time we're singing just the two of us...
ね、すごい楽しかったですし、またね、呼んでくださいよ、奏ちゃん。奏ちゃんのためならいつでも飛びますよ。
Right, it was really fun. Please invite me again, Kanade-chan. I'll fly over anytime for you, Kanade-chan.
ぜひぜひ！
Please do!
生でハモリという、すごい難しい難題を一緒に飛び越えられて嬉しいです！
I'm so glad we were able to overcome the extremely difficult challenge of doing live harmonies together!
飛び越えたね！
We jumped right over it, didn't we!
嬉しかったですね！
It was wonderful!
頑張りました、私たち！ぜひともね、アーカイブも残るしね、何回も聞き返してほしいですね。
We did our best! The archive will be up, so I hope everyone listens to it over and over again.
はい、ぜひ！
Yes, absolutely!
ということで、奏さん、この後もまだまだ続くと思いますが、頑張ってください！
So, Kanade-san, I know there's still more to come after this, but do your best!
ありがとうございます！本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
それでは、失礼します！
With that, I'll take my leave!
はい、ありがとうございました！
Yes, thank you so much!
さあ、ゲストの皆さんにね、たくさん盛り上げていただきました
Now, our guests have hyped things up so much,
ということで、ここからはソロでですね、頑張っていきますよ！
so from here on out, I'll be doing my solo performance and giving it my all!
ということで、まだまだ盛り上げていきます！
Let's keep the energy going!
その前にちょっと、準備とお水を飲んでくるので、待っていてください！行ってきます！
Before that, I'll go get ready and drink some water, so please wait a moment! See you soon!
ここからは一気に5曲、いっちゃいます！
From here on, I'm going to perform 5 songs in a row!
最後に...
Lastly...
し、し、し、し、し...
S-S-S-S-S...
シークレットだもん！
It's a secret!
最後のお楽しみにということで。
Please look forward to it at the end.
それでは、次の曲聞いてください。
With that, please listen to the next song.
All Alone With You
All Alone With You / 作詞・作曲：ryo (supercell)
[Song: All Alone With You / Lyrics & Composition: ryo (supercell)]
Yeah...
Ah...
誰かを愛することなんて 出来るわけなくって
There's no way we could ever love someone else,
だけど誰かに愛されたくて
but we want someone to love us.
変わらない昨日がずっと続いたとしても
Even if yesterday went on never changing,
どこにも行けやしないんだ
we can't go anywhere at all.
私とキミ
You and I...
神さま どこへ行ってしまったの ねえ
Lord in heaven, where have you gone? Please...
返事はなくて いつだってそうだよ
...there is no response, it's always like this.
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone あなたと行く
You'll never walk alone, I'll go with you.
どんな罪も
No matter your sin,
背負ってあげる
I'll shoulder it for you.
道なき道を
I'll walk the unpaved paths...
歩いてくの あなたと二人で
...all alone with you.
こっちにきて 私に触れてキスをして
Come here, touch me, and kiss me.
もっとめちゃくちゃに したっていいんだよ
It's okay for you to mess me up even more, you know?
いつか誰もが死んじゃって 忘れられてくなら
If everyone will die one day and be forgotten,
今確かなものだけを信じるわ
right now, I'll believe only in something concrete.
神さま気取りの人が言うの
Pretentious people who act like gods say...
ねえ 人は強いって
...'Hey, people are strong.'
そんなの嘘だよ
That is a lie.
Do you agree?
I will stay with you あなたの手で
I will stay with you, with your hands...
抱きしめてよ
...embrace me...
思いっきり
...with all your strength.
怖がらなくて
Don't be afraid.
もう大丈夫
You'll be alright.
私なら
I'm here for you.
その手が汚れてしまったとしても
Even if your hands are stained beyond cleansing,
愛してほしい
I want you to love...
私のこと
...me.
You'll never walk alone あなたと行く
You'll never walk alone, I'll go with you.
どんな罪も
No matter your sin,
背負ってあげる
I'll shoulder it for you.
道なき道を
I'll walk the unpaved paths...
歩いてくの あなたと
...with you.
I will stay with you
優しく愛でて
Cherish me gently
思い通り望めない
Since there's nothing but things
ものばかり
that don't go the way I want...
何もないから
...and I have nothing else,
あなたと
I want to be with you,
二人で
just the two of us.
あたたかい涙で
With warm tears
ふいに目覚めた
I suddenly woke up
あぁ 枯れた夢の続きは保存
Ah, where is the continuation of
どこにあるの？保存
the withered dream?
さびしいよ
I'm so lonely
Please give it back
いつかになれば保存
If someday comes,
楽になれる
will I find peace?
寄せては返す
Waves that wash ashore and return...
波に抗って
...I resist them
白い枕に
On the white pillow,
寝ぼけたままの顔
my half-asleep face...
うずめて
...I bury it
同じ夢を
The same dream...
願うほどに保存
...the more I wish for it,
冴えていくよ
...the more awake I become
Please give it back
代わりなんていないよ
There is no replacement for you
あなたの匂い保存
Your scent...
思い出せない
...I can't even remember it
波にさらわれて
Swept away by the waves
夢の続きを保存保存
The continuation of the dream...
捕まえに行くから保存
...I'm going to catch it,
待ってて
so please wait for me
いつの間にか
Before I knew it,
孤独ぶるには
to act all lonely,
優しさに触れすぎた
I've touched too much kindness
沁みていく
It sinks in
顔を上げてみようか保存
Shall I try raising my face?
一人じゃないって
That I'm not alone...
信じてみたい保存
...I want to believe that,
信じてみたいの
I really want to believe it
Please give it back
生まれたばかりの保存
Just newly born...
淡い光に保存
...in that faint light,
希望を見たの
I saw hope
胸が熱いよ
My heart is burning
手を握ってよ
Hold my hand
迷わないよ
I won't get lost
終わり
The end
明日からまた保存
From tomorrow again,
選んだ道を保存
on the path I chose,
進めるように
so I can move forward
おらあ！まだまだ行くぞ！
All right! We're still going!
ぶつかって 逃げ込んで 僕は
Colliding, running away, I...
いつしか ここに立ってた
...before I knew it, was standing here.
誰もが 憧れる ヒーローに
I wanted to become a hero...
なりたくて でもなれなくて
...that everyone admires, but I couldn't.
これくらいじゃ 届かないこと
I knew that like this, I wouldn't reach it,
分かっていたのに
even though I knew that.
敗北の少年 現実を謳え
Defeated boy, sing of reality.
あんな風に 空は飛べやしないんだ
You can't fly in the sky like that.
こんな泥に 意味があるなら
If there's meaning in this mud,
僕らは地を這う
we will crawl on the ground.
耳鳴りか 谺して僕に
Is it a ringing in my ears echoing to me?
奇跡が 問いかけるんだ
Or is a miracle questioning me?
君の夢 憧れたヒーローに
To the hero your dreams admired,
今すぐ させてあげよう
I will let you become him right now.
雨みたいに 差し伸べられたって
Even if it was reached out to me like rain,
嬉しくないんだ
I wouldn't be happy.
敗北の少年 旋風を謳え
Defeated boy, sing of the whirlwind.
君みたいに眩しくはなれないけど
I can't be radiant like you, but...
こんな泥に 意味があるなら
If there's meaning in this mud,
僕らは地を這う まだ地を這う
we will crawl on the ground, still crawl on the ground.
あぁ...
Ah...
鼓動を知って 息を吸い込んで
Feeling my heartbeat, taking a deep breath,
僕は遠慮するよ
I'll pass.
敗北の...
Defeated...
敗北の少年 平凡を謳え
Defeated boy, sing of the ordinary.
あいにく神は信じないタチで
Unfortunately, I'm not the type to believe in God.
すれ違いの 物語よ サヨナラ
Goodbye, to our passing story.
敗北の少年 現実を謳え
Defeated boy, sing of reality.
僕らは泥を吐き這いつくばるもの
We are those who spit mud and crawl.
こんな泥も 愛おしいから
Because even this mud is beloved,
僕らは地を這う ただ地を這う
we will crawl on the ground, just crawl on the ground.
あのね
Hey...
I say "私、大丈夫?"
I say, 'Am I okay?'
Maybe, うまくやれるはず
Maybe, I should be able to do it well.
ずっと走った 息継ぎもしないまま
Running all the way without even taking a breath.
あっそう、終わりが来るなら
Oh, if the end is coming,
別に寂しくなんかはない
it's not like I'm lonely or anything.
真実は 心の奥の方
The truth is deep in my heart.
自分のことすら 愛せないまま
Without even being able to love myself...
ないまま
...without even taking a breath...
君のこと守れるのかな
can I protect you?
どうか 正心正銘のこの思いを聴いて
Please, listen to this truly genuine feeling of mine
私 全身全霊で歌うから
because I will sing with all my heart and soul
大丈夫 世界はこんなに綺麗だと
It's okay, I understand that the world is so beautiful...
分かってる 分かってる 分かってる 分かってるよ
I know, I know, I know, I do know!
ごめんね じれったい
I'm sorry, it's frustrating.
足りない こんなんじゃ誰 mo aisenai no
It's not enough, I can't love anyone like this
止めない 止まることは知らないの
Don't stop, I don't know how to stop
言葉足らず 失くしてしまう物ばかりだ
I'm just lacking words, constantly losing things
Luna say maybe...
降るのは 迷be, rainy
It's falling, Maybe, rainy
愛せ どんな自分でも
Love yourself, no matter who you are
Maybe, ネイビー色に染まるまで
Maybe, until it is dyed in navy
時間はかかるかもしれないけど
It might take some time, but...
I know, 輝くしかないこと
I know, there's no choice but to shine
ハイライト 塗り続けるしかない
Highlight, I have no choice but to keep painting it
真実はちゃんと 言わなくちゃね
I have to speak the truth clearly, right?
目に見えるものが
To things that can be seen...
続くと、ずっと そう、ずっと
continuing, forever... yes, forever.
君に 半信半疑な素振りして
Acting half-doubting towards you,
心 空回り 遠回り
My heart spins in circles, taking detours
最低だ もう一回やり直せるのなら
It's the worst, if I could redo it one more time,
素真になりたい なりたい なりたいと 願ったジレンマ
I want to be honest, I want to, I want to... my wished-for dilemma
このまま 1人じゃ何もできない
At this rate, I can't do anything alone
全部 決めるのは 自分次第
Everything is up to me to decide
初めて背中をみた時に
When I first saw your back,
覚悟を決めた どこまで
I made up my mind. How far...
いけるのか
can I go?
届くのか
Will I reach it?
わからないよ
I don't know...
臆病がそこに立っている
Cowardice is standing right there.
3秒前バックステージ 震える背中を君に預けて
3 seconds before backstage, I entrust my trembling back to you
この運命的出会いは きっと
This fated meeting is surely...
そう、きっと
...yes, surely...
偶然みたいな
...like a coincidence.
多分、神様のいたずらです
Perhaps, it's a prank by God.
どうか 正心正銘のこの思いが
Please, until this truly genuine feeling of mine...
君の心(ところ)にちゃんと届くまで
...reaches your heart properly.
ここで 私 全身全霊で歌うから
Here, I will sing with all my heart and soul, so...
待ってる 待っている
I'm waiting, I'm waiting,
だから、この場所を大切にしたいの
So, I want to cherish this place.
これが 正心正銘の私なんだ
This is the truly genuine me!
大丈夫 もう怖くはないわ
It's okay, I'm not afraid anymore!
たまにつまずくことならあるけど
Sometimes I might stumble, but...
一番特等席で 君の笑顔見たいんだ
I want to see your smile from the very best seat
私だけの特権
My exclusive privilege
見えない未来 手探り今日も
Even today, groping through an unseen future...
ステージの上で 証明してみせるから
I'll prove it to you on this stage!
ここにしかないスクリーンに
On the screen that only exists here...
君にまだ話せてないこと
There are still things I haven't told you...
ばかりあるんだ
...so many of them.
聞いてほしいの
I want you to hear them...
あのね...
You see...
はあ... みんな、見に来てくれて本当にありがとう！
Phew... Everyone, thank you so much for coming to see me!
最後は新曲をお届けします。
Lastly, I'll be delivering my new song.
聞いてください。
Please listen.
You & 合図
[Song: You & Aizu]
目覚めの合図
The signal of awakening
スマホが踊る
My smartphone dances
...の合図
...our signal.
もう一歩を
Take one more step...
踏み出して
Step forward,
踏み出して...
step forward,
合わせてみよう
let's match them together!
なんでマンデー
Why is it Monday?
どうしてサンデー
Why is it Sunday?
明日へ弾んでいたいの
I want to keep bouncing toward tomorrow!
タクトをシュッ・シュッ
Baton: Swish, swish!
拍手をパン・パン
Applause: Clap, clap!
ここからはすべてダ・カーポ
From here on, it's all Da Capo!
日曜日の...
Leaping over...
コーダを飛び越えて
Sunday's Coda!
待ってるよ
I'm waiting!
明日よ...
Tomorrow...
来ないでと願ってしまうほど
wishing so hard that it wouldn't come!
(La La La)
あなたを...
Even the time...
待ちわびる時間すらも愛おしい
waiting for you is lovable!
一歩前に
One step forward,
レガート深呼吸
legato deep breath!
スタッカートで
Staccato...
二度の瞬き Compass
two blinks!
月曜の約束を
Let's play our Monday promise!
奏でよう
Let's play!
ねえ、
Hey...
君と僕の合図
the signal between you and me!
(Na Na Na)
奏でよう
Let's play!
ね、叶うよ
Yeah, it will come true!
私たちだけの合図保存
The signal only for us two!
なんと！最後の曲は、奏自身の2作目の
オリ曲、「You & 合図」でしたー！パフパフ！
And that! The final song was Kanade's second
original song, "You & Aizu"! *Trumpet sounds*!
てれれん！可愛いでしょう、新曲のジャケ写です！
Tada! Isn't it cute? This is the jacket art
for the new song!
このあと24時、えっと21日の0時、あ、0時、
ちょっと噛んじゃいました、21日の0時から配信開始です！
After this, at 24:00—rather, at 0:00 on the 21st...
ah, 0:00... I bit my tongue a little, it starts streaming from 0:00 on the 21st!
もうね、すごく可愛い振り付けとなっているので
良かったら踊ってみてね！
The choreography is super cute,
so please try dancing to it if you like!
さらに、この配信のあとMVも、
えっと21時10分からプレミア公開されます！
Furthermore, after this stream, the MV will also
have its premiere starting at 21:10!
もうこちらの楽曲ですね、あの歌詞もちらっと
見えていたから分か... ちょっと気づいてるお前らもね、
たくさんコメント欄でさ、ムカムカしていたと思うんですが...
With this song, since you could see glimpses
of the lyrics... I think some of you noticed and were
probably itching to say something in the comments, but...
あの月曜日だったり、奏の要素がいっぱい込められている、
そういう楽曲となっているので良かったらね、あの、
いっぱい聴いてください！
It's a song filled with Kanade-like elements,
including references to Monday, so I hope
you listen to it a lot!
はい！
Yes!
えっと、ということで皆さんお待ちかねのグッズ情報も
行って参りたいと思います！MVも見てね！
So, let's move on to the merchandise info that
you've all been waiting for! Be sure to watch the MV too!
えっと、えっと、音乃瀬奏生誕記念グッズ2026！
ぱんぱかぱーん！可愛い！
Um... Otonose Kanade Birthday Celebration
Merchandise 2026! *Fanfare*! So cute!
配信開始はこのあと21時20分からだから安心してい
最後までちゃんと見ていってね。順番にしょって、
紹介していきます。まずは、こちら！てれれん！
Sales start after this at 21:20, so don't worry, relax and
make sure to watch until the very end. I'll introduce
them in order. First, this one! Tada!
奏と待ち合わせ！ポストカードフレーム！
Kanade and Rendezvous! Postcard Frame!
今回のキービジュアルを「奏と待ち合わせ」をテーマに
gomziママに描いていただきましたので、日常のワンシーンを
飾るイメージで作ってみました！可愛いでしょう！
For this key visual, we had gomzi-mama draw it based on
the theme "Rendezvous with Kanade", so we made it
with the idea of decorating a scene from your daily life! Isn't it cute?!
そのままでも楽しめる他、他のポストカードだったり挟んで、
別の絵柄で楽しむこともできます。2つ目は、こちら！
In addition to enjoying it as it is, you can also
slide other postcards inside to enjoy different designs.
The second item is this!
また奏が落書きしちゃったwTシャツ！
Kanade Scribbled Again T-Shirt!
奏の落書きTシャツ第2弾！本当に今日は、月曜日！
もう月曜日盛りだくさんです。ハッピー月曜日！
This is the second volume of Kanade's scribble T-shirts!
Today really is Monday! Yes, it's packed with Mondays.
Happy Monday!
ということで月曜日Tシャツです。毎週月曜日にはこの
Tシャツを着てね、良かったら生活してください。
最高、ありがとう！えっと、3つ目は、こちら！
So, it's a Monday T-shirt. Please wear this T-shirt
every Monday to live your daily life.
Awesome, thank you! Okay, the third item is this!
奏とおそろネックレス！可愛いでしょう！
Matching Necklace with Kanade! Isn't it cute?!
今回キービジュアルの奏との、おそろいの、
奏モチーフのネックレスです。確か、デビュー日が
書かれているはず。です、奏の。良かったら...
This is a Kanade-motif necklace that matches
the one worn by Kanade in the key visual.
I believe her debut date is engraved on it. Yes, Kanade's. If you like...
えっと、すごいシンプルでスタイリッシュなデザインに
落とし込んでみたので、普段アクセサリー着けないよっていう
人もぜひお手に取って着けてみてください。そして4つ目、こちら！
Um, we made it into a very simple and stylish design,
so even if you don't usually wear accessories,
please pick one up and try it on. And the fourth one is this!
「明日は月曜日w」ひょっこりぬいぐるみ！
"Tomorrow is Monday lol" Peek-a-boo Plushie!
いやもうね、こちらの素敵な、もう素敵なフリップを持った
奏のぬいぐるみです。画面モニターとかに引っ掛けて
飾ることができますので、いつでも上から奏が
「月曜日だよ〜」ってお知らせいたします、イェーイ！
Yes, this is a Kanade plushie holding that wonderful,
wonderful sign. You can hang it on your screen monitor or
elsewhere to display it, so Kanade can notify you
from above anytime, "It's Monday~" Yay!
最後に、フルセット購入特典！ぱんぱかぱーん！として、
数量限定で直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード、
通常版は箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードと、
ボイスがついてきます！今回のボイスは、奏の...
Finally, the Full Set Purchase Bonus! *Fanfare*!
It comes with a limited-quantity handwritten autographed
postcard with a hot-stamped printed message, while the
regular version includes a printed autographed postcard with
a message, plus a voice pack! This time, the voice pack features Kanade's...
い、いろいろ決意表明！
A-And various declarations of determination!
おまえらへの感謝とこれからの意気込みを
Expressing my gratitude to you guys and my enthusiasm for the future...
ありのまま伝えるフリートークボイスになっています！
...just as it is in this free-talk voice!
ボイスはフルセットを購入したら必ずついてくるから
This voice is guaranteed to be included with the full set,
安心してね！
so don't worry!
以上、グッズ紹介でしたー！
And that is all for the merchandise introduction!
みんな、今日は...
Everyone, today is...
月曜日だね。
Monday, isn't it?
そんな月曜日のおまえらには...
For you guys on such a Monday...
どーん！
Ta-da!
犬！
A dog!
今回は犬です！今日は月曜日ということで
This time it's a dog! Since today is Monday,
犬のフリップ、今年ね、
here's a dog flipbook! This year,
エイプリルフールネタを擦っていきますよ。ワン！
I'm going to milk the April Fools' joke. Woof!
えーっと、このあとメン限にて
Um, after this, in the members-only stream,
アンコールライブもやっちゃうよー！
I'm also doing an encore live stream!
このQRコードは何なんだ？
What is this QR code?
アンコールではちょっとおまえらのリクエストに
During the encore, I might respond to...
答えたりするかも？
...some of your requests?
うん、このQR、あ、あ、いけないいけない！
Hmm, this QR... Ah, ah, no, no, no!
おまえら読み込んでしまう！
You guys are going to scan it!
このQRを読み込んだら、えーっと、
If you scan this QR, um...
メンバーシップに入れるみたいです。うん、見せないでおこう。
It looks like you can join the membership. Hmm, I won't show it.
ふぇー、見せないでおこう。
Phew, I won't show it.
えっ、見せちゃおうかな、どうしようかなー。
Eh, maybe I should show it, what should I do~
はい、えーっと...
Alright, um...
それじゃあ、あの、今日は本当にあの
Well then, um, today, I really want to...
奏のライブに見に来てくれてありがとうございました。
...thank you so much for coming to watch Kanade's live stream.
全編生ライブというすごい奏にとっても挑戦的なライブでして、
It was a fully live performance, which was extremely challenging for me,
本当はめちゃくちゃ怖かったんですけど、
and to be honest, I was absolutely terrified...
あの、なんとかかんとかすごくポスト、Xだったり、
...but somehow, thanks to all the posts on X,
おまえらがこう応援のメッセージを送ってくれたおかげで、
and you guys sending supportive messages,
すごく、もう緊張もそんなにせず終えられたかなと思います。
I think I was able to finish without feeling too nervous.
本当に見に来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming to watch!
それでは、メン限アンコールライブでまた会おうね！
Well then, let's meet again in the members-only encore live stream!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
またね！
See you!
チャンネル登録してね！
Please subscribe to the channel!
見に来てくれて本当に、本当にありがとうございました。 正直、すごく怖かったけど...
[Text: Thank you so, so much for coming to watch. Honestly, I was really scared, but...]
...おまえらが応援してくれたから 最後までやり遂げることができました。
[Text: ...because you all supported me, I was able to see it through to the end.]
これからもおまえらに前を向ける歌を届けられる奏でいられるように、
[Text: So that I can continue to be Kanade and deliver songs that help you look forward,]
いっぱいいっぱいがんばります。ついてきて！ - 奏
[Text: I will do my absolute best. Follow me! - Kanade]